Guide to the Delmer Daves Papers, 1930-1965
Department of Special Collections
- Destination Tokyo, (Warner Brothers), 1943
  - Test scenes for Mike and the Kid, The Captain, Pills, Wolf, and Tin Can. Carbon typescript with scattered pencil holograph noyations., N.D.; 15 pages
- Los Angeles Evening Herald-Express: article by Jimmy Star about1Delmer Daves., 8/25/43
  - Ink sketches and floor pland of submarines by Delmer Daves, with a notation in ink holograph: Sketched from S. type submarine, Mare Island May 1943, Delmer Daves, 5/43; 4 pages
  - Queries by Delmer Daves. Questions on actions of script. Ribbon typescript with occasional pencil and ink holograph notations. 11 pages Included with above: Cast of characters in pencil holograph. 2 pages, N.D. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - a.) Directorial notes by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with pencil sketch of submarine on 1st page. pages Top right corner 1st page: Delmer Daves-(since I never directed a test scene before. I had a lot to cram fast!) written in ink holograph by Delmer Daves., N.D. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - b.) Pencil holograph notes [by Delmer Daves] on 16 m.o., 6 pages
  - Advertisement for new book by Tom E. Manners- Song of Seas and Tall Ships., N.D. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Inter-office communication: T.C. Wright to producers and directors re: eliminating continuity sketches. Mimeo, on octavo. 1 page, 7/8/43 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Pencil and ink sketches of scenes made at Mare Island by Delmer Daves. Each page has 6 sketches 2×2-5/8. Some sketch work on verso of pages, and 2 pages of sketches on complete pages., 6/11-6/13/43; ca. 109 pages (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - a.) List of camera shots, each with corresponding 2×2-5/8 photocopy of ink and watercolor scene sketch. 4 to a page, on 4×10" sheet of photographic paper. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 27 pages (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - b.) List of camera shots, identical to `a.'. Carbon typescript with occasional pencil holograph notations., 27 pages (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Summary of scenes to be shot that require Navy cooperation., 5/14/43; 4 pages (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Revised camera shot breakdown. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 6 pages
  - List of photographicand information required. Carbon typescript., N.D.; 1 page
  - List of camera shots at different locations., N.D.; Mimeo- 4 pages (2 copies)
  - Scene breakdown of revised temporary script., 5/25/43; Mimeo- ca. 144 pages (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - At work on Destination Tokyo. Photograph (8×10") of Johnny Garfield, Delmer Daves, Art Lueker, Jerry Wald., 1943 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Enlarged (8×10") photocopies of ink and watercolor scene sketches., N.D.; 30 prints
  - Galley proof (first edition) of Battle Below, The War of the Submarines by Robert J. Casey., 1943; ca. 127 pages (Box 16, Folder 8)
- The Very Thought of You (Warner Brothers), 1944
  - Complete shooting script, screenplay by Alvah Bessie and Delmer Daves from an original story by Lionel Wiggins. Mimeo- with occasional pencil holograph changes, and continuity sketches by Daves in some margins and on verso of same pages. All sketches in pencil, and most 1 ×1½. Included with original script are revisons, also mimeo, on blue paper, with dates of 3/3, 3/4, 3/9, 3/14, 3/21, 3/30, and 4/10/44.Total pages: ca. 190 On verso last page: list of 17 names in pencil holograph probably actors being considered for potential roles in movie. Front cover: typed below title, Shooting script- with my continuity sketches here and there, primitive rubber-stamp apertures., N.D. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Revised temporary script by Alvah Bessie. Mimeo- with some casting suggestions in red pencil holograph on `cast of characters' page. ca. 150 pages Title page: note by Delmer Daves in ink holograph This is the first script sent to me on completeing Destination Tokyo-I liked the love theme, loathed the slum clearance aspect-conferences resulted in 2nd rev. temp. (see) but was still wrong for me-so Jerry Wald asked me to write a final version (see shooting script) Front page: hand-lettered in ink [by Delmer Daves] Alvah Bessie Draft #1 (New York City Version), and in pencil holograph top of page, `Jerry Wald' [signiture]., 10/4/43 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 2nd revised temporary script, screenplay by Alvah Bessie. Mimeo-with pencil shading along margins denoting `Daves' material. ca. 160 pages Introductory page: note by Delmer Daves in ink holograph, This script was rejected by Warner and Wald-I was asked to do a rewrite and given complete freedom to reject or retain material from this-in the shooting script I wrote I retained 37% of this script in feeling or fact (marked). I had objected to the New York `slum clearance' confusions of the 1st draft-but he changed only to Pasadena at my suggestion as director assigned and too few of my other suggestions-so final screenplay=63% Daves script/37% Bessie- Fronttcover: ink holograph top of page [by Delmer Daves] Alvah Bessie Draft #2 (Pasadena)., 2/3/44 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Hollywood Canteen (Warner Brothers), 1944
  - Photographs (8×10") of ink and charcoal sketches for camera shots., N.D.; 19 prints (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Pencil sketches of scenes by Delmer Daves. Each page has 12 sketches, (1-7/8×2-3/8), most sketches labeled in pencil holograph., N.D.; 26 pages (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Cast lists for men and women. Ribbon typescfipt. 2 pages (includes numerous Hollywood `stars'), N.D.
  - Temporary script, original screenplay by Delmer Daves. Mimeo-with scattered pencil and ink holograph additions and deletions, including some on verso of same pages. Included with original script are revisions, also mimeo, on blue paper, with dates of 10/29; 11/11; 12/10/43.Total pages: ca. 115 pages Pasted in front of title page: one scene (165) in carbon type-script, with pencil holograph changes., 10/15/43 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Staff and cast list. Mimeo-1 page Bottom of page: note by Delmer Daves, exact text as follows, The production of Hollywood Canteen was postponed until 1944 when the Actors' Guild protested the use of stars in bit roles-demanding they be paid full salary, even if only appearing for one day!! Obviously impossible, -picture was postponed pending change of ruling. Made possible because of the 40% profits to the Canteen (the fund existed for some years invested and growing under Jules Steins' management)-Lasky left WB, so I made the 1944 version with Sottlieb producer-, 11/27/43 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Temporary script. Mimeo- includes same revisions as #6., 10/15/43; ca. 115 pages (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Temporary script (same as #6 and #8), 10/15/43; Mimeo- ca. 115 pages (Box 17, Folder 9)
- The Mississippi Belle (Warner Brothers), 1942-45
  Note by Delmer Daves on box: This story was started and stopped twice-even though Cole Porter wrote fine score for it-the decline of the musical plus lack of singing star shelved it in 1945
  - Outline for a musical picture based on the novel by Clements Ripley. Mimeo- 76 pages Front cover: `Delmer Daves' in pencil holograph [by Daves] across top right of page., 11/27/42 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Notes on the original material plus the rough draft treatment. Ribbon typescript with scattered pencil holograph additions and deletions, including 1 page of pencil holograph notes by Delmer Daves., N.D.; ca. 139 pages (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Research for film. Includes:, N.D. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - a.) Floor plan of Mississippi steamboat. Photocopies, (8½×11") 2 pages
    - b.) Irish proverbs. Ribbon type-script., 3 pages
    - c.) Research notes for Mississippi Belle. Ribbon typescript., ca. 23 pages
    - d.) Irish exerpts from O'Malley of Shanganagh. Ribbon typescript., 3 pages
    - e.) Miscellaneous notes. Ribbon typescript. 2 pages Last page: `Mississippi Belle' in ink holograph as title.
  - Revised treatment by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript., 11/3/42; 22 pages (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Treatment by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript. 101 pages (3 copies of this treatment, all identical), 11/2/42 (Box 18, Folder 5-7)
- Pride of the Marines (Warner Brothers), 1945
  - Sergeant Schmidt - Marine by Roger Butterfield. M. with Wald 10/22/43 hand-lettered in pencil on title page., 10/15/43; ca. 109 pages. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Al Schmidt Correspondence in scrapbook., 1942-1943 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - a) Copies (carbon typescript) of letters to Ruth Hartley (Schmidt's fiancee) and letters to his relatives., ca. 33 pages.
    - b) Copies of newspaper articles on Schmidt, ca. 40 pages.
    - c) 2 photocopies of newspaper articles on Schmidt and friends.
  - Screenplay by Albert Maltz, adaptation by Marvin Borowsky. Carbon typescript ca. 177 pages. Inside back cover: pencil holograph notes by D.D., 9/12/44 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Screenplay by Albert Maltz (unbound). M. with occasional pencil holograph changes., ND; ca. 163 pages. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Revised temporary script. M with scattered pencil holograph additions and deletions. ca. 189 pages. Front cover: Delmer Daves hand lettered in pencil on top left of page., 10/4/44 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Incomplete final script - screenplay by Albert Maltz from biography by Robert Butterfield. M. ca. 125 pages. Title page: note by DD in ink holograph exact text as follows: I had numerous suggestions on reading Albert Maltz's October 4, 1944 script - mostly regarding the love scenes - and the need for rough humor amongst the Marines, especially after wounded - Albert said he wasn't good at this, suggested I take over the `sentiment and humor' re: writing - so I did - his commentary on my version follows - (see final shooting script), 10/24/44 (Box 19, Folder 2, 3, 4)
    Part I 50pp.
    53pp
    1/28/44
    Part II
    11/1/44 17pp.
    Part III
  - Suggestions and criticisms by Albert Maltz. Typed letter signed: Albert Maltz to Jerry Wald. Followed by criticisms: carbon typescript, with scattered holograph notations in charcoal pencil. 18 pgs., 12/2/44 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Complete shooting script with changes. M. with FPpNAD including some scene sketches (1 × 1 1/2") in margins. Included with original script are revisions, also M., on blue paper with dates 2/8/44 (ca. 39 pgs. of changes)., ND; Total script: ca. 162 pgs. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    ALSO - 1 page of sketches and notes
  - Ink and charcoal sketches of scenes. 12 per page, 1 7/8 × 2 3/8" each., ND; 53 pages. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Photograph (5 × 7") of John Garfield-star of movie., ND (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Dialogue transcript copyright 1945. M. Legal. 65 pages. Front cover: Jerry Wald in pen top left page. Date June 26, 1945 in pencil top left., 6/26/45 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - 20 BW photographs of N.Y.C. (3 - 5 × 7 in.; 17 - 5 × 8 in.). with numbers and some scene references and descriptions in ink., ND (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Photocopies (8 × 10"), BW, of scene drawings. 6 prints, 2 with typed explanation on vso.., ND (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - This Love of Ours (Pride of the Marines) - Guadalcanal sequence transcriptions by Katherine Lewis. Reels #1 - 3. C. Legal., ND; 8 pgs. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - IOC T. C. Wright from DD re: scene shots. C. with pencil numbers and with principals added., 11/1/44; 4 pgs.
  - IOC DD to T. C. Wright re: list of sets. C., 11/2/44
  - IOC T. C. Wright to all producers and directors re: keys and steriopticon shots. C., 1/4/45
  - IOC DD to Jerry Wald to Charles Einfeld re: changing title., 4/30/45
  - Crossroads, A. A. F. Redistribution Station No. 4. Vol. 1, No. 5., 12/23/44
  - Outline and development of story by scenes., ND; 9 pgs.
- Task Force, Part 1 (Warner Brothers), 1945
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] to Jerry Wald and Delmer Daves re: Navy films. Carbon typescript., 5/9/45; 9 pages (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] to Jerry Wald re: Navy film. Carbon typescript., 5/10/45; 6 pages
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] to Jerry Wald. Carbon typescript. 7 pages, 5/13/45
  - Typed letter: H.B. Miller (Secretary of the Navy-Director of Public Relations), to Chief of the Bureau of Aeronautics re: selecting of classified Navy film for use by Warner Brothers. Carbon typescript., 5/14/45; 1 page
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] to Jerry Wald re: Navy films. Carbon typescript., 5/15/45; 4 pages
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] to Jerry Wald re: Navy films about Japanese suicide missions. Carbon typescript., 5/16/45; 2 pages
  - Typed letter: H.A. McDonald, Comdr. USN(ret.), to Chief, Bureau of Aeronautics re: request for stock film. Carbon typescript., 5/16/45; 1 page
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] to Jerry Wald re: Navy films. Carbon typescript., 5/18/45; 2 pages
  - Description of sequence with Secretaty of State, Charles Evans Hughes, the Under-Secretaly, and 3 Assistant Secretarys leaving the State, War, and Navy Buildings. Carbon typescript., N.D.; 3 pages (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] to Jerry Wald re: Navy films. Carbon typescript., 6/1/45; 3 pages
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] to Jerry Wald re: Navy films. Carbon typescript., 5/22/45; 3 pages
  - Typed letter: David Hopkins, Lieut., USNR, to Jerry Wald re Navy films. Carbon typescript., 6/25/45; 2 pages
  - Typed letter: David Hopkins to Jerry Wald re: research material. Carbon typescript., 6/25/45; 2 pages
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] to Jerry Wald re: footage from Pathe, 1920's. Carbon typescript., 6/21/45; 4 pages
  - Typed letter George Boggs to Jerry Wald re: Navy films. Carbon typescript., 6/15/45; 3 pages
  - Typed letter: George [Boggs] and Earl Colgrove to Jerry Wald re: Navy films. Carbon typescript., 6/4/45; 2 pages
  - 8 sketches of LSO signals., N.D.; 1 page
  - Air Force- list of selected stock film., N.D.; Mimeo- 21 pages (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Feature film reviewed and selected by Delmer Daves; list and detailed description of shots. Carbon typescript., 4/19/45; ca. 50 pages (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Naval Aviation-Its Problems, Etc. From 1922. Author unknown. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 20 pages (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Statement by Lt. Jensen on Midway and Task Force 58. Carbon typescript with scattered pencil changes., 7/26/45; 6 pages (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - List of positions in any CV*9 Class CIC (nerve center of Task Force). Carbon typescript., 10/3/45; 8 pages
  - Passing of the Word During Ships' Routine. Ribbon typescript., 9/26/45; 1 page
  - Typed letter signed: Lt. Comdr. Richard Winn, USNR, to George Dorsey re: enclosed copy of Navy Day address by Vice-Admiral Carney., 10/25/48; 1 page
  - Notes on 4 nautical statistics. (3"×5" paper) Hand-lettered in pencil., N.D.; 1 page
  - Fighter Squadron 152- flight schedule submitted by Lt. Charles Baumeister. Mimeo- 1 page On verso: service and home add dress of two naval officers, hand-lettered in ink., 10/21/48
  - Suggested CIC operations. Ribbon typescript with frequent pencil holograph notes, changes, and deletions., N.D.; 11 pages (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Positions in CV-9 Class CIC operations. Carbon typescript., 10/3/45; 16 pages
  - Pilots and Aircraft Totals by Years-1911 to 1944. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - America's Prime Weapon-Carrier Based Aviation by Rear Admiral Dewitt C. Ramsey. (reprint from Aviation magazine) Ribbon typescript., 6/44; 4 pages
  - VPB-The Patrol Bomber by Rear Admiral John S. MECain (reprint from Flying and Popular Aviation). Ribbon typescript., 1/42; 3 pages
  - VF-The Fighter by Lt. Comdr. John B. Pearson, Jr. (reprint from Flying and Popular Aviation). Ribbon typescript., 1/42; 4 pages
  - Attached with above: Navy news release: TigerCat is New Navy Twin-Engine Fighter Bomber., 6/7/45; Mimeo- 1 page
  - VSB-The Scoyt Bomber by Lt. Comdr. J.N. Murphy (reprint from Flying and Popular Aviation). Ribbon typescript., 1/42; 3 pages
  - VT-The Torpedo Plane by Lt. Comdr. Steadman Teller (reprint from Flying and Popular Aviation). Ribbon typescript., 1/42; 3 pages
  - VOS VSO-Observation and Scouting by Lt. Comdr. M.K. Fleming (reprint from Flying and Popular Aviation). Ribbon typescript., 1/42; 2 pages
  - Attached with above: Navy news release, Navy's New Observation Scout Plane Undergoes Baptism In Borneo Invasion., 6/15/45; Mimeo- 3 pages
  - Folder containing:, .. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - a.) Information on 6 U.S. carriers. Ribbon typescript., 1 page
    - b.) Short biography of 2 Navy career officers. Ribbon typescript., 1 page
    - c.) Organizational structure list of Carrier Air Department! Ribbon typescript., 1 page
    - d.) Arguements against carriers and carrier planes. Ribbon typescript., 1 page
    - e.) Chronicle of U.S. history by years, 1921-1944. Each yearly report includes fashions, finances, domestic and foreign policy, and naval status., ca. 67 pgs.
  - Washington and N. Y. Interviews with various Navy personnel. SpNA., ND; 3 pgs.
  - The Returning Servicemen by Max Silverstein, Council of Social Agencies, Los Angeles. Paper prepared for the Writers' Congress seminar. M., ND; 6 pgs. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Naval Aviation and the Influence of its Missions on Carrier Based Aircraft - speech made at Annual Summer Meeting, Institute of the Aeronautical Sciences, Los Angeles, by Rear Admiral T. C. Lonnquest, U. S. Navy. M., 7/16/48; 15 pgs. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Sea Power for Peace - address delivered before the Chautauqua Institute by Vice-Admiral A. W. Radford. M., 7/10/48; 7 pgs. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Address by Rear-Admiral T. C. Lonnquest before Aviation Division, N. Y. Board of Trade. M., 8/4/48; 6 pgs. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - The Fast Carrier Task Force - remarks by Rear-Admiral R. A. Ofstie before the Metropolitan Section, Aviation Writers Association, M., 6/30/48; 11 pgs. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Statement of the Honorable John L. Sullivan, Sec. of the Navy, before the Senate Armed Services Committee. M., 6/1/48; 6 pgs. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Research notes on Carrier Story. Includes: Carrier Story by Max Miller; notes about Navy wives by Dorothy Bonney; Keep Fleet, Says Rayburn (reprint of newspaper article); The Story of McCluskey - notes by DD. M., ND [2/13/45]; ca. 219 pgs. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Preliminary compilation and research material for Task Force. Prepared under the direction of Herman Lissauer - Head of Research Department, by James A. Smith: -- copy of contents following -- approximately 35 typed copies of articles plus relatec photos., ND (Box 20, Folder 15-16)
    See Contents on next page
  - Notes on activities and operation of radio and radar room. Pencil. Legal., ND; 22 pgs. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Washington and New York Interviews, Delmer Daves., 3 pages (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Will We Choose Naval Suicide Again? Statement by the Honorable James Forrestal, Secretary of the Navy. United States Government Printing Office, 1944.12 pages Included in above: photograph (8×10) of Forrestal. (Box 21, Folder 15)
    also included - Title page, of item # 43 Contents pages(2), and 1"×3" tag that was on the outside of original notebook
  - A Navy Flyer's Creed. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Background for War. 1853-1941.Ageton. Naval Officer's Guide. Carbon typescript., 7 pages
  - Japanese History, 1914-1936.Yakhontoff. Eyes on Japan. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - The Lansing-Ischii Agreement, 1917.Bisson. American Policies in the Far East. Ribbon typescript., 1 page
  - Background for War. Wilson's attitude toward Russia. Villard. Fighting Years. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Russian Revolution. Barnes. History of Western Civilization. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Washington Treaty, 1922-23.Banning. The Fleet Today. Bisson. Op. Cit. Bailey. A Diplomatic History of the American People. 2 pictures (8×10). 1 picture (13×18) from the Illustrated London News, Dec. 10, 1921,pages 786-87. Carbon typescript., 2 pages
  - 18 pictures (8×10): people and places involved in Washington Disarmament Conference of 1922.
  - Japanese Exclusion. Harcourt-Smith. Fire in the Pacific. Bailey. Op. Cit. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Morrow Board. Nicholson. Dwight Morrow. Carbon typescript. 1 page Included in above: 11 pictures (8×10) of Morrow Board and Senate Investigating Committees.
  - Tanaka Report, 1927.Henderson and Morris. War in Our Time. Carbon typescript. 2 pages Included with above: 2 pictures (8×10) of Tanaka and Chinese war-lord.
  - Briand-Kellogg Pact, 1928.Dictionary of American History. Carbon typescript. 1 page Included with above: 3 pictured (8×10) of signing of Pact.
  - London Treaty, 1930.Banning. Op. Cit. Barnes. Op. Cit. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Japans Foreign Policy, 1931.Muir. A Brief History of Modern Times. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Black Dragon Society. Henderson and Morris. Op. Cit. Carbon typescript. 1 page Included with above: 6 pictures (8×10) of Japanese leaders.
  - Genesis of World War II. Japan conquers Manchuria. 1931.Henderson and Morris. Op. Cit. Carbon typescript. 2 pages Included with above: 3 pictures (8×10) of Henry L. Stinson; extent of Japanese conquest in 1932; Japanese leaders.
  - World Disarmament Conference at Geneva, 1932.3 pictures (8×10); 1 picture (12½×18½) from Illustrated London News, Feb. 20, 1932.
  - Quotations: Senator Pittman and editorials, 1935.Premier Okada, 1936.Takahashi, 1936.Hirota, 1938.Nye and Vandenberg, 1940.Rhee. Japan Inside Out. Carbon typescript, 2 pages
  - Treaty of Berlin, 1940.Roosevelt's Foreign Policy. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Tojo, Konoye, Hirohoto, etc., 9 pictures (8×10).
  - Japan's Seven Points of 1941listed. Brown. Suez to Singapore. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Miscellaneous Quotations: Japanese Army pamphlet, Normura, etc. Byas. The Japanese Enemy. Carbon typescript., 2 pages
  - Roosevelt's Foreign Policy. Memorandum on bombing of the Panay, Sept. 1941.Declaration of War, etc. Roosevelt's Foreign Policy. Carbon typescript., 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Quotations: Tokyo and Matsuoka. 1941.Roosevelt's Foreign Policy. Carbon typescript, 1 page Included with above: 6 pictures (2=8×10, 4=snapshot size) of Japanese political leaders.
  - Pearl Harbor., 6 pictures (8×10).
  - Brief Naval History, 1921-30.Armitage. United States Navy. Carbon typescript., 4 pages
  - Naval Aviation: Outstanding Men and Events. Carbon typescript. 2 pages Included with above: 5 pictures (8×10).
  - Statistics on naval aviation development, etc. Armitage. Op. Cit. Carbon typescript., 2 pages
  - North Island, San Diego. Hotel del Coronado., 8 pictures (8×10).
  - 5 pictures (8×10): U.S. Navy officers.
  - Aircraft Carriers. Banning. Op. Cit. Carbon typescript, 2 pages
  - Carrier Chatter. Collier's. November 27, 1943.Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Battle of Midway. The Navy at War. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Langley, Jap Bomb Victim. Los Angeles Times. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Naval Construction. Henderson and Morris. War in Our Time. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Langley, Saratoga, Lexington and a few modern carriers. 35 pictures (8×10). 23 prints and 12 photocopies. Also: 2 photocopies (8½×13½) of carriers Lexington and Saratoga.
  - Portfolio of Navy planes., 21 pictures (8×10).
  - Miscellaneous: French carrier Bearn, 1928.American gunboat patroling Yangtze, 1927.Reception room door, Secretary of the Navy., 3 pictures (8×10).
  - Nomenclature of Japanese warships. Launer. The Enemy's Fighting Ships. Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Prelude to World War II. Arrest of the Six by I.F. Stone. Nation. 1945.Carbon typescript., 1 page
  - Portfolio of Ubiforms. Uniform Regulations. United States Navy. 1922.And designs by M.O. Best. Warner Brothers., 47 pictures (8×10).
  - Screenplay by Ranald MacDougall. Mimeo, ribbon, and carbon typescript with scattered pencil holograph changes throughout. Mimeo- ca..132 pages Carbon typescript- ca. 79 pages Ribbon typescript- ca. 18 pages, N.D. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Aircraft Carrier Story- index. (14 point historical outline) Carbon typescript., N.D.; 15 pages (Box 21, Folder 4)